Adam DeLessio

Falls Church, VA | (908) 635-7204 | adamdelessio@gmail.com

Github: Adam-DeLessio | LinkedIn: adam-delessio

Active Clearance: Secret

Summary

With a unique blend of experiences in computer programming, music education, and military training, I bring a focused, thoughtful, and efficient approach to web development. I look for the less obvious solutions, adapt to changing needs, and embrace a challenge to meet and exceed the expected goals.

Skills

HTML/CSS	Javascript	React.js	Node.js	Express
Mongoose	MongoDB	Python	Django	SQL

Projects

Tower of Hanoi: Recreation of the classic block-stacking game.

> Tech Used: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Deployed: https://adam-delessio.github.io/Tower_of_Hanoi/

National Parks: Uses the National Parks API for data and a mockup for the interface.

> Tech Used: React

Github: https://github.com/Adam-DeLessio/national-parks

Breweries API: Back end to a larger project. Provides a JSON view of several Virginia breweries.

> Tech Used: MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.is

> Deployed: https://mysterious-lowlands-53459.herokuapp.com/

Contact Book: Command line application with full CRUD capabilities.

> Tech Used: Python, PeeWee, SQL

Github: https://github.com/Adam-DeLessio/python-cli-project

Experience

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive

Washington D.C.

Student

Nov. 2019 - Feb. 2020

> 500 hour program focused on the real-world application of essential software engineering practices, and high-level exposure to the most relevant technologies available.

United States Marine Drum and Bugle Corps

Washington D.C.

Sergeant - E5

Nov. 2015 - Nov. 2019

- > Performed in hundreds of ceremonies nationally and abroad for tens of thousands of audience members, to include a number of dignitaries and heads of state.
- > Small unit leader tasked with ensuring music and marching proficiency, timely and efficient travel, and equipment accountability of more than ten Marines.

Education

The Catholic University of America
Bachelor of Music in Music Education

Washington D.C. Aug. 2011 – May 2015